EZRA HAZELL

1241 N KINGSTON ST. GILBERT, AZ 85233 | (480) 687-1996 | EZRA.HAZELL@GMAIL.COM | WWW.EAZYDEZIGNS.NET

Profile

A web developer with over 20 years of experience programming as a front-end developer. Have at least 10 years of experience developing websites using WordPress and Drupal. All websites, applications, and interfaces have enhanced features like user interactive elements and are responsive to optimize user experience and online presence across mobile and desktop platforms.

Experience

Sr. Web Developer, AZ Dept of Water Resources; Phoenix, AZ - 7/2015-present

- Manage and supervise a small team of designers and developers for the department's Web Team.
- Managed and maintained 6 of the department's websites.
- Responsible for high-quality designs, graphics, mock-ups and layouts for both new and existing web applications.
- Created custom themes for our websites that use the Drupal CMS platform.
- Migrated and re-designed all static websites into Drupal using custom templates and themes.
- Installation and setup multi-development environments of Drupal 7 & 8, programming, database setup/administration, thorough testing, and QA.
- Use Git for source control and drush for Drupal configuration and management.
- Design mock-ups and wire-frames for web content.
- Developed online solutions for full websites, microsites, mobile websites, social media marketing campaigns, and email marketing deployments.
- Work closely with project managers, digital strategists, and communications team to develop solutions with the use of new and emerging technologies.
- Present ideas, reports/analysis, and updates on projects to clients and account managers.
- Make necessary updates and edits to websites content to enhance user experience that comply with state government and accessibility requirements.

Web Developer, Defero; Phoenix, AZ — 9/2014-6/2015

- Developed online solutions including full websites, microsites, Facebook applications, mobile websites, and email marketing deployments.
- Worked closely with project managers, strategists and our creative studio to develop solutions with the use of new and emerging technologies that fits with the client's needs.
- Created custom themes for each of our client's websites to match with their branding using Drupal 7.
- Set up development environments, installation of Drupal and WordPress solutions, programming, database setup/administration, thorough testing and QA.
- Presented ideas, reports/analysis, and updates on projects to clients and account managers.
- Presented ideas on projects to clients and account managers that were request for proposal (RFP). Responded to technical questions about web projects.
- Made necessary changes to websites content.

EZRA HAZELL

1241 N KINGSTON ST. GILBERT, AZ 85233 | (480) 687-1996 | EZRA.HAZELL@GMAIL.COM | WWW.EAZYDEZIGNS.NET

- Maintained the health of websites by verifying all backups were completed as scheduled and that the websites were all up to date with the latest security, plugin, and module updates.

UI Designer, Arizona State University; Scottsdale, AZ - 6/2013-5/2014

- Created intuitive user interfaces and interaction layers using best practices, the latest Web trends and all available tools to augment the user experience.
- Responsible for high-quality designs, graphics, mock-ups and layouts for web prototypes.
- Created UI designs that are W3C compliant and using HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery for increased user interaction.

Web Design Intern, U-Haul Inc.; Phoenix, AZ — 7/2013-12/2013

- Designed, developed and implemented new websites and landing pages.
- Created intuitive user interfaces and interaction layers using best practices, the latest Web trends and all available tools to augment the user experience.
- Created user interfaces that are responsive and can be used across multiple mobile and desktop devices.
- Created user and web interfaces that utilized the best UX practice that is W3C compliant and used HTML5, CSS3, and jQuery for increased user interaction.
- Used the CSS framework, Foundation components to develop the websites.

Freelance Web Designer/Developer — 1997 - present

- Design mockups and wireframes for web content that are W3C compliant.
- Each project is designed and coded using HTML/HTML5, XML, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS/CSS3 languages, WordPress and Drupal content management systems, and using original or custom graphics.
- Create intuitive user interfaces and interaction layers using best practices, the latest Web trends and frameworks like Bootstrap to augment the user experience.
- Create websites that are responsive using the mobile-first approach and can be used across multiple mobile and desktop devices.

Technical Support, PerceptIS; Phoenix, AZ — 8/2009-6/2013

- Answered user inquiries regarding computer software or hardware operation to resolve problems.
- Identified, troubleshoot, and resolved the causes of computer, application, and network problems, using diagnostic testing software and equipment.

Network Engineer, American Express, Phoenix, AZ — 5/2008-9/2008

- Served as the last level of support in troubleshooting network usage and equipment.
- Configured and maintained the network with Force 10 switches, Cisco Routers, and Cisco Switches. Maintained and managed network using Cisco 2500, 2600, 3500, 5000 5200, 6000, and 6500 series switches with Gigabit Ethernet modules.
- Configured and administered networks using several WAN protocols: BGP, EIGRP, and OSPF.

EZRA HAZELL

1241 N KINGSTON ST. GILBERT, AZ 85233 | (480) 687-1996 | EZRA.HAZELL@GMAIL.COM | WWW.EAZYDEZIGNS.NET

Network Support, Information Strategy Design, Scottsdale, AZ — 5/2007-10/2007

- Installed, Configured, Troubleshoot and resolved all hardware issues on workstations, servers, laptops, printers, scanners, network faxing, hand-held devices, routers, switches and wireless connectivity issues via phone and onsite support.
- Troubleshoot and resolved software issues for a variety of software applications and operating systems.

Computer Systems Specialist, US Army — 4/2001-4/2007

- Maintain and administer computer networks and related computing environments including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations.
- Installed network systems and servers at any given location to provide network and client-server support for over 500 users and subscribers.

Web/Graphics Designer & Mentor, S.T.A.R. Center, Fairfax, VA — 9/1997 – 4/2001

- Assisted faculty and students with various media projects in designing graphics and/or web sites.
- Taught classes in HTML, Photoshop, and Illustrator to faculty and students.
- Designed graphics for all brochures, flyers, and newsletters for various campus organizations.
- Designed and maintained web sites for various local and campus organizations.

Education

Arizona State University, Tempe, AZ

➤ BAS Internet and Web Development – 2013

Iowa Central College, Fort Dodge, IA

> AAS Computer Networking - 2011